# MINH TRAN

Herndon, VA 20171 ◆ (703) 674-9000 ◆ tranminh631@gmail.com

https://tranminh631.github.io/

## Professional Summary

Hardworking Software Developer in Test offering 3 years experience and expertise necessary to plan, develop, test, and secure dynamic and complex software systems. Open and clear communicator with good multitasking skills, organized nature and strong attention to detail. Helps teams produce exceptional products by offering in-depth quality assurance support. Background writing and implementing test cases, developing testing plans and identifying use cases. Fully versed in complete Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC). Strong background in automated functional and security testing. Interested in shifting career to Information Security industry.

# SKILLS

- Web Security
- Technical Support
- Test implementation
- Cloud implementation and installation
- Debugging and troubleshooting systems
- Developing and implementing security plans/tests
- Customer support
- Testing and maintenance

- Security Analysis
- Customer relationship development
- Software maintenance
- Data security
- Product development
- Forecasting and Planning
- Requirements Analysis
- Process improvement

#### WORK HISTORY

#### Full-Stack Freelance Web Developer, 01/2020 to Current

Self – Herndon, VA

- Conducted security audits to identify 100% of Open Web Application Security Project Foundation (OWASP Top 10) vulnerabilities.
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Conducted integration testing of modular front-end and back-end to promote site effectiveness over course of web development lifecycle.
- Determined coding requirements for site creation, including user interface, security and specialized scripts.
- Oversaw technical web issues and troubleshooting requests to resolve surfaced problems.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed

requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.

- Provided ongoing efficiency and security maintenance and patching on website interface to maintain viability after launch.
- Assisted web presence planning, implementing changes and integrating requested elements to streamline business operations.
- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating well-organized project plans.

## Software Developer in Test, 06/2018 to 01/2020

#### FINRA – Rockville, MD

- Attended Security Testing committee meetings to propose, discuss, and advance CISSP certification education for Quality Assurance department and evaluate a 20+ hour training course.
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Identified and tracked defects with Java and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- Reviewed violations of computer security procedures via creation of Access Control Matrices and System/Flow diagrams and developed mitigation plans.
- Created accurate and efficient JUnit test scripts to manage automated testing of certain products and features.
- Gathered data on integration issues and vulnerabilities across all components and reported all findings, including improvement recommendations.
- Authored and maintained well-organized, efficient and successful test cases for entire team.
- Assessed software bugs and compiled findings along with resolution techniques in documentation to disseminate to software testers.

### **Junior Software Developer in Test**, 06/2017 to 06/2018

#### Ettain (Contractor For FINRA) – Rockville, MD

- Collaborated on all stages of systems development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Prepared test plans and over 50 test cases based on Options and Fixed Income securities requirement documents for Java.
- Performed software testing to uncover bugs and troubleshoot big data (ETL) issues prior to application launch.
- Designed validation and quality assurance parameters for automated test of AWS cloud migrations.
- Experience with supporting high-load big data applications.
- Ensure validity of cloud migration database architecture via test scripts.
- Generate detailed test reports and documentation for tracking of testing efforts.
- Drove adoption of service-oriented architecture (SOA) during conversion from local solutions to cloud-based services.

#### **Web Developer Intern**, 06/2016 to 08/2016

#### **Perfect Sense** – Reston, VA

- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.
- Reviewed projects for compliance with specifications and quality standards.
- Collaborated with development, quality assurance, and designers to develop web products.
- Oversaw creation of 20+ major new modules to a new software system.
- Managed full-cycle design implementation tasks, handling all phases from conception to completion while maintaining responsive and functional specifications throughout.
- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quick-loading sites with particular layouts.
- Worked in Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Pinpointed user experience issues to devise targeted suggestions for creating cohesive user experience.

#### **Web Developer Intern**, 06/2015 to 08/2015

# **Perfect Sense** – Reston, VA

- Designed and implemented over 10 web components across Special Olympics website.
- Investigated and resolved application issues for web-based programs providing end-user support.
- Collaborated with product managers, testers, and developers to initiate process improvements.
- Oversaw back-end development using Java to maintain website integrity, security and efficiency.
- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Built outstanding and dynamic team of software engineers and developers which significantly boosted overall success of organization.
- Collaborated with designers to develop new applications system to enhance client requirements for web computing capabilities.

EDUCATION -	
Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science, 12/2016 Virginia Tech - Blacksburg, VA	
——————————————————————————————————————	

- ISTOB Certified Tester (18-CTFL-02026-USA)
- Google Ads Search Certification https://skillshop.exceedlms.com/profiles /08f10ae5d7c9405b848a19d36e0affe0
- CompTIA Security+ (In Progress)